By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
the State of Qin began its invasion of the State of Wei.
秦国(しんこく)は 魏国(ぎこく)へと侵攻した
The enemy blocking their way is the legendary Great General, Lian Po.
立ちはだかる敵は
伝説の大将軍 廉頗(れんぱ)
Young generals take on this relentless battlefield in hopes of rendering great military achievements.
若き将たちは 大いなる武功を狙い
この苛烈な戦場に挑む
One night after the Feixin Unit, Yufeng Unit, and Yuehua Unit launched their attack on Lun Hu's headquarters...
飛信(ひしん)隊 玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊 楽華(がくか)隊による
輪虎(りんこ)本陣急襲から一夜明け…
（廉頗）フン…
（楚水(そすい)）信どの？
Lord Xin?
（信）
ハハハッ… さすがに見えねえか
Guess he can't see me.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦いの中心で
命を懸けている男たちは―
And at the center of all of this, the men risking their lives in battle
不思議なことに察していた
sensed something mysterious.
（蒙驁(もうごう)）フッ… やはり そうか
I thought so.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）これから 山陽(さんよう)大攻略戦
その最後の日の 幕が開けることを
The curtain now opens on the final day of the war to capture Shanyang!
Whadda ya mean we're in the rear reserve unit?!
俺たちが後方予備隊って
どういうことだよ？
What do you expect after acting on your own so much yesterday?
（栄備(えいび)）昨日 あれだけ
勝手をしておいて 当然じゃろうが
ンンッ… あと 何じゃ？
And what's with that attitude?!
The Yuehua, Yufeng, and Feixin Units will all be getting along here as a rear reserve unit today.
その口の利き方は
（殴る音）
（栄備）楽華 玉鳳 飛信３隊は
今日は 仲良く後方配備だ
Rear... unit...?
（渕(えん)）後ろ …ですか
（尾平(びへい)）やっぱ そうだよな
Yeah, makes sense.
But General, what about the morale
we worked so hard to raise!
だけど 将軍
これじゃ せっかく上がった士気が
フッ… まあ そう ぼやくな
Quit complaining.
Lun Hu will probably come out again.
恐らく また輪虎は出てくる
それなら お前たちにとっては―
When that happens, being a reserve unit won't be such a bad deal for you guys.
予備隊も悪くなかろうが
（信）えっ？
（楚水）将軍の
おっしゃるとおりです 信どの
The general is correct, Lord Xin.
（楚水）陣の前方に組み込まれたら
If he cuts into the formation from the front,
運よく そこに輪虎が
攻めてこなければ 出会えませぬ
unless you're lucky enough to be the unit Lun Hu attacks, you won't encounter him.
But if you're a reserve unit that is covering a wide range,
しかし 持ち場の
広い後方予備隊なら―
いつでも対応できる
（信）ああ そっか！
you can adapt to any situation.
Oh, right!
So basically, general, you're giving us permission to...
てことは 将軍は俺たちに輪虎を…
Normally, you'd be torn limb from limb for violating military laws...
本来ならば 軍律違反で
八つ裂きにすべき お前らだが
フン… まあ
あの輪虎の本陣を突いた その力は
But seeing as you managed to penetrate Lun Hu's headquarters,
わしも土門(どもん)も本物だと評価している
both Tu Men and I have judged your ability to be genuine.
So don't blunder next time, Xin.
次は しくじるなよ
信！
（信）ウッ！ ゴホッ…
So until that opportunity arises, you can just stare at my ass from behind!
では その機が来るまで
後ろで わしのケツでも眺めておれ
（栄備）今朝の雲は厚いなぁ
We've got some thick clouds today.
今日は荒れそうじゃのぅ
Looks like it'll be a stormy day.
The Hour of Conclusion
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）流尹(るい)平野の戦い ６日目
蒙驁は 従来どおり―
Day 6 of the battle on the Liuyin Plain.
As he has up until this point, Meng Ao has positioned horizontal units as the main defense,
横陣(おうじん)という守備主体の構えを敷いて
魏国軍を迎え撃つ態勢だった
and has prepared for an attack on the State of Wei Army.
At the right wing is General Tu Men.
右翼には土門将軍
左翼には栄備将軍を配し
And stationed on the left wing is General Rong Bei.
At the rear of the right wing is the Yuehua Unit and the Yufeng Unit
右翼後方に楽華隊 玉鳳隊
Behind the left wing is the Feixin Unit.
左翼後方には飛信隊が予備隊として
それぞれの持ち場に就いている
All three as reserve units ready at their positions.
そして 中央軍後方の高台には
蒙驁の本陣があり―
And on the high ground behind the central army is Meng Ao's headquarters
where he surveyed over the Liuyin Plain.
流尹平野を見渡していた
（輪虎）
介子坊(かいしぼう)さんの補充兵は まだ？
Are the reserve soldiers from Jie Zifang here yet?
（輪虎兵）まだです
Not yet, sir.
失った僕の兵は介子坊の兵で埋める
I will fill in my lost soldiers with Jie Zifang's.
しかし 重量級の彼らが―
But I wonder how well those heavyweight-class soldiers will be able to keep up with my fighting style.
僕の戦い方に
どこまで ついてこられるか…
Though the State of Wei soldiers are the same on that point.
最も その点に関しては
魏国兵も同じだけれども
General Lun Hu!
（魏良(ぎりょう)）
輪虎将軍 貴殿は勘違いされておる
You are mistaken!
これは 廉頗将軍をはじめとする
あなた方の復帰戦にあらず
This is not your nor General Lian Po's comeback war.
これは 秦国の犬どもの侵略から
国を守る我々 魏国人の戦いだ！
This is our, the citizens of the State of Wei's war to defend our land from those State of Qin dogs!
Everyone is here to protect their country and their families.
みな国を
家族を守るために 戦いに来た
その思いを その命を―
We are entrusting all of those feelings and lives to you in these battles!
全て あなたに預けて戦うのだ！
（輪虎）ハッ…
Please, put a bit more trust in our abilities.
もっと我々の力を信用してくだされ
我々が
将軍の兵の力に及ばないのなら―
And if our power is not as great as that of your soldiers, General,
we will make up for what we lack with emotion!
足りない分は
気持ちで埋めてみせまする
Good. We should be amply able to fight with this.
よし… これは これで 十分 戦える
We'll start without waiting for Jie Zifang's soldiers.
介子坊の兵を待たずに始めるぞ
Your name is Wei Liang, right?
魏良 …だったね？
Yes, sir!
今日 狙うのは 敵中央軍の
後ろにいる総大将 蒙驁の首だ
Today, our target is the head of Supreme Commander Meng Ao, located at the back of the enemy central army.
I need everyone to fight with the fury of desperation.
みんなには
死にものぐるいで働いてもらうよ
Yes, sir!
It looks like those State of Wei soldiers suddenly had a boost in morale.
（番陽(ばんよう)）魏国のヤツら
急に士気が上がりましたな
Wh-What do you make of this, Lord Meng Tian?
（じい）蒙恬(もうてん)さま こ… これは…
（蒙恬）やるね
He's good.
I suppose today really is going to be the critical moment.
やはり 今日が本番ですね
（信）ああ
Yeah.
Come at me, Lun Hu!
来い 輪虎
All units, charge!
（輪虎）全軍…
突撃！
Kill them!
（魏兵）
殺せ！ 秦国の犬どもを殺せ！
Kill the State of Qin dogs!
（楚水）前衛の全てが
猛攻を受けているようです
Everyone in the vanguard are meeting with a fierce attack.
Mr. Yuan, can you see Lun Hu?
渕さん 輪虎は見えるか？
（渕）ここからでは何とも…
Not yet...
Though we may have a large station in the rear,
後方で 持ち場が広いとはいえ
やはり輪虎と当たるかは運しだいか
hitting Lun Hu is still going to depend a lot on luck.
The enemy army has the upper hand.
（朱可）敵軍の力が偏っている
輪虎は右にいるもようです！
Lun Hu seems to be on the right!
Lord Meng Tian, it seems the side that was hit was ours and the Yufeng Unit's side.
蒙恬さま
どうやら 当たったのは我々と―
玉鳳隊のようですな
Prepare to leave at any moment!
いつでも出られる準備をしておけ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（土門）ひるむな！
Do not falter!
Now's the time to show them the fury of the Great State of Qin Army!
大秦国軍の恐ろしさ
今こそ見せてやれ！
Lord Xin! The battle on the right seems quite intense!
信どの 右の戦闘が激しいようです
Do you think Lun Hu could be on the right?!
まさか 輪虎は右翼に…
あれは違う
（楚水）えっ？
No, he's not.
今日の輪虎は 本気で来る
Today, Lun Hu is going to attack seriously.
あいつが出たら
絶対あんなもんじゃねえ
Once he gets going, you can bet it's not gonna be anything like that.
The enemy's inner-ranks have started moving...
奥の敵が 移動を始めた
The right-wing enemy is turning in... the opposite direction?!
右翼の敵は 逆方向に旋回している
What... What is going on here?!
何だ？ 何が起こっているのだ？
What?! There's a huge dust cloud rising over there!
（兵士）何だ！
（兵士）
前に すごい砂煙が上がっているぞ
（郭叫(かくきょう)）蒙驁将軍 あ… あれを！
General Men Ao, o-over there!
巨大な渦が２つ…
There are two giant vortexes!
They're... gradually moving forward?
（朱可）ゆっくり 前に進んでる…
（蒙驁）“輪動(りんどう)”
Wheel movement.
わしもウワサでしか聞いておらぬが
かつて 輪虎は―
I had only heard rumors of it, but supposedly Lun Hu
輪動という特異な戦術で―
penetrated Wang Qi of the Six Great Generals' defense unit using a wheel movement.
あの六大将軍 王騎(おうき)の守備を
貫いたといわれておる
ええい！ 何か仕掛けてくるぞ！
左右の軍に厚みを作れ！
They're going to try something!
Thicken defenses in the right and left armies!
（側近１）ははっ！
Yes, sir!
General Rong Bei's reaction was quick!
（朱可）栄備将軍の対応も早い！
（郭叫）
渦の前に兵を送って 分厚くした！
He sent soldiers to the front of the vortexes!
（兵士）
ウワーッ！ ヤツらを止めろー！
Stop them!
Their momentum is too strong!
（兵士）この勢いはムリだ！
ンンッ… こ… これが輪動の正体か
S-So this is the true form of the wheel movement?
With the two vortexes spinning in opposite directions,
互いに 逆方向に回転する渦は
横陣の力を左右に分けてしまう
they separate the horizontal formation's strength to the left and the right.
そして そこに生じた隙間に―
And in the opening that creates...
the end of the wheel breaks into the defense in a pyramid shape!
輪動の先端が
キリのように突入していく
Oh no. The target of that wheel movement is...
いかん　あの輪動の攻撃の的は…
Rong Bei's formation!
栄備の陣じゃ
They failed, huh?
しくじったか…
Lord Ben! There's a change at the left wing!
賁さま！ 左翼で異変が！
Lord Meng Tian!
蒙恬さま！
The Feixin Unit's station?
飛信隊の持ち場か…
Captain!
隊長！
（信）ああ
Yeah.
間違いねえ
No doubt about it...
It's Lun Hu!
輪虎だ
Lun Hu
What a fighting style...
（魏良）なんという戦い方だ
ついていくだけで兵の体力が…
Just keeping up with him is taking all of our soldier's stamina...
しかし
これほどの突破劇も初めてだ
But I've never felt such a vehement charge!
Do not falter, State of Wei soldiers!
ひるむな魏国兵！ ここが正念場だ
This is do-or-die!
（側近１）く… 来るぞ！ 守れ！
（側近２）将軍 お下がりを！
H-Here they come, defend!
General, get back!
General, hurry!
将軍 お早く！
（側近２）栄備将軍！
General Rong Bei!
（栄備）ンンッ… ハアッ！
輪虎め… どうやら格が違ったか
Lun Hu... It looks like we're not in the same league.
せがれほどの若者に
あとを託さねばならぬとは…
I actually need a bunch of punk kids to have my back...
Even if I am no match for Lun Hu, I can at least get one strike in on him!
かなわぬまでも
せめて輪虎に ひと太刀
Lun Hu!
輪虎ーっ！
Please, my lord... I wish you good fortune in this war...
どうか 殿…
ご武運を…
W-What happened?
（朱可）ど… どうなった？
栄備将軍の旗が消えたぞ
General Rong Bei's flag disappeared!
（郭叫）ま… まさか…
It-It can't be!
Rong Bei...
栄備…
After losing a general, the State of Qin soldiers will be paralyzed.
将を失ったせいで
秦国兵の統制はマヒしている
Now to charge straight to the headquarters.
あとは 一気に本陣を突くだけ
Th-This is bad!
（郭叫）マ… マズイぞ
His momentum brought him all the way through the horizontal unit.
あの勢いで横陣を突破されたら―
Now the only thing between him and this headquarters is a few reserve units!
あとは この本陣との間には
僅かな予備隊しかいない
蒙驁将軍！
General Meng Ao!
Lun Hu...
輪虎… ンッ！
Okay, let's go, you bastards!
よし 行くぞ てめえら！
（伝者）待て 飛信隊！
全兵で動いてはならん！
Wait, Feixin Unit!
We can't have all soldiers moving!
Why, old messenger guy?!
な… なんでだよ？ 伝者のおっさん
With this enemy right in front of us, we'll still need some on standby.
この正面の敵で
まだ待機している軍がいる
Just to be safe, leave 200 here before you go!
念のための予備として
200は ここに置いていくんだ！
That's insane!
（楚水）バカな！
The natural thing to do would be to attack with all of our soldiers!
全兵をもって当たるのが
当然であろう！
ならん！ 命令だ！
（信）クッ…
No! This is an order!
渕さん！
Mr. Yuan!
Hurry and pick 200 men from the heavily injured!
急いで
ケガの重いヤツから200人集めろ
Ah, yes sir!
えっ？ あっ はい！
Qiang Lei, I'm leaving leadership of the people here to you!
（信）
羌瘣(きょうかい) ここの指揮 お前に任せるぞ
He's leaving Lord Qiang Lei?!
羌瘣どのを置いていく？
まさか ケガをしているのか？
Could he... be injured?
（楚水）
やはり 輪虎兵に囲まれたときに…
It must've been when we were surrounded by Lun Hu soldiers.
It's pointless to be fussing over me...
（羌瘣）妙な気遣いは無用だ…
そんなんじゃねえ　今日の戦いは
何が起こるか分からねえから―
I'm not!
I don't know what's gonna happen in today's fight,
200の指揮をお前に頼むんだ
so that's why I'm asking you to lead 200!
Remember, I've gotten plenty of protection from you.
それに お前の援護は十分もらった
Qiang Lei, I'll see you later.
羌瘣
また あとでな
Right.
All right!
Let's go, you bastards!
行くぞ てめえら！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Stop!
（兵士）止めろー！
（兵士たち）ウワーッ！
（魏良）よ～し！
もはや敵に我らを止めるすべはない
All right!
The enemy has no way of stopping us now!
蒙驁本陣まで一気に攻め落とすぞ！
Keep mowing them down until we make it to Meng Ao's headquarters!
You've lost, State of Qin dogs!
秦国の犬ども！ 貴様らの負けだ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
輪虎ーっ！
Lun Hu!
隊長に続けー！
Follow after the captain!
（斬る音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
（朱可）あっ… 将軍
General!
うむ…
The enemy has stopped moving!
（朱可）敵の足が止まった…
You're not getting away again. I won't let you!
もう逃げねえし 逃がさねえぞ
It's time to settle this, Lun Hu!
決着の時だ
輪虎！
Vice Captain Qiang Lei...
（兵士）
羌瘣副長… 大丈夫ですよね？
Are the captain and the others... going to be okay?
隊長たちは…
I'm surprised.
驚いたな　その右腕
当分 使えないと思ったけど
I thought you wouldn't be able to use that right arm for some time.
This guy, with one hand, he's...
こいつ 片手で…
Looks like you can't use your left arm anymore, huh?!
（信）てめえの左腕は
使い物にならなくなったようだな
Xin! The left! Go for his left side with his crippled hand!
（去亥(きょがい)）信！ 左だ！
手が使えない左に回り込め！
You don't need to tell me!
言われなくても分かってらぁ！
It's impossible.
ムリだ… 輪虎は 巧みな馬術で
回らせないようにしている
Lun Hu will use his deft horse-riding skills to turn that side away from him.
And despite the fact that his left hand was mutilated yesterday, he's still fighting coolly.
しかも 昨日
左手をやられたにもかかわらず―
平然と戦っている
Under Lian Po, this man really must have survived scenes of carnage that we can't even imagine.
やはり ヤツは廉頗のもとで―
我々の想像を絶する修羅場を
くぐり抜けてきたのだ
Xin...
信…
（李充(りじゅう)）あっ…
殿 後ろが どうかされましたか？
My lord!
Is something happening behind us?
う～む…
What?
なに！ こいつ 昨日より…
Is this guy even stronger than before...?!
ウワッ！
Xin!
信！
You'd best not make the mistake of thinking I'll be weaker today than I was yesterday.
僕が昨日より弱っているなんて
勘違いしちゃダメだよ
I've got tons of experience of only being able to fight with one hand.
片手が使えない戦いなんて
いくらでも経験してきたし
何より
今日は このあと約束があるんでね
But most of all, I have a "promise" to fulfill after this today.
Promise?
約束？
（守備兵１）
正面 盛り上がってんな
Sounds like things are really heating up at the front.
ちくしょう やっぱ外れだ
Man, we really got the short straw.
後ろの見張りなんて
ずっと山見てるだけだぜ
All you get to do as the rear guard is to stare at mountains.
（守備兵２）バカ 真面目にやれ
You idiot, get serious!
The back of this headquarters is comparatively less steep.
この本陣 後ろは比較的 傾斜が緩い
If you're the enemy, your only choices are to force your way through the front or go around to the back.
敵にすれば
正面を強行突破するか―
後ろに回り込むしかない
But you can't send a large army to the back, right?
（守備兵１）だが
後ろに 大軍は送り込めないだろう
No. They could definitely pull off a surprise attack.
いや 奇襲攻撃程度なら
十分 展開できる
かっ… そんなんで
本陣が落とせるかよ　ムダムダ
No way, man. The headquarters could never fall to something like that.
ア～ッ… 正面の戦い 見物してえよ
実際に戦うのはイヤだけど
I wanna see the battle in the front.
Not that I wanna actually fight, though.
おい
（守備兵１）うん？
Hey.
どうした？
（守備兵２）何だ？ あれは
What's wrong?
What's that?
あっ 騎馬 …だな
It's a... mounted soldier, right?
て… 敵か？
（守備兵１）さあ… でも１騎だぞ
A-An enemy?
Dunno. But it's just one.
Who is that guy?
（守備兵２）何だ？ あいつは
殿…
My lord?
Hey, Meng Ao!
（廉頗）こら 蒙驁！
へっぴり腰が直ったか
廉頗さまが見に来てやったぞ！
Have you gotten over your weak nerve?!
Lord Lian Po is here to see ya!
Did he say Lian Po?!
廉頗だと！
（守備兵）バカな！ 本物か？
No way, is that really him?!
I definitely felt a sense of intimidation from him...
しかし あの威圧感は確かに…
（守備兵）ウワサ以上の大男だぞ
He's even bigger than the rumors said!
なぜ こんな所に１人で！
Why is he at a place like this alone?!
M-My lord, is that truly Lian Po?
（馬令）と… 殿
あれは まさしく廉頗では？
バカな…
It can't be...
Lian Po... You remembered me, did you?
廉頗…
覚えておったのか わしのことを
さっさと下りてこい！
一騎打ちでカタをつけるぞ
Hurry and get down here!
We'll settle this one-on-one!
なっ！ い… 一騎打ち？
（守備兵）本気で言っているのか！
O-One on one?!
Is he being serious?!
そんなもの
蒙驁さまが受けるはずがない
There's no way Lord Meng Ao would accept something like that!
We did it plenty of times in the past, didn't we?!
（廉頗）
確か 昔 何度かやったであろうが！
ほれ！
貴様が小便漏らして逃げ出した―
I'm pretty sure you always pissed yourself and turned tail!
あの続きをやろうと
言っておるのじゃ　来い 蒙驁！
I'm saying we continue that!
Come, Meng Ao!
I don't mind fighting empty handed!
こっちは素手でも かまわんぞ！
殿…
My lord...
The way he teases people hasn't changed a bit.
人の おちょくり方も
変わっておらぬわ
But I'm actually quite happy with this.
だが それは それで うれしいわい
Okay, let's get started!
（蒙驁）よし 始めるぞ！
（馬令）ははっ！
Yes, sir!
Take your positions!
配置に就け！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Call every soldier!
（兵士）全兵を呼べ！ 急げ！
Hurry!
ノリ悪し ハハハハッ…
Looks like he's not game for it.
Hey, look!
お… おい あれ
Okay, shall we get going?
さ～て やるかい
The Final Plan
End